<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects | Ritwika Sen</title>
    <link>https://ritwikasen.github.io/projects/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://ritwikasen.github.io/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Projects</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language>
    <image>
      <url>https://ritwikasen.github.io/media/icon_hu7bf344ec5ea801f354f438dfa0ab14a8_4721_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://ritwikasen.github.io/projects/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Employment Within the Firm</title>
      <link>https://ritwikasen.github.io/projects/01_sewif/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ritwikasen.github.io/projects/01_sewif/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Abstract&lt;/b&gt;: We study the internal organization of manufacturing firms in Uganda. We measure what people do within firms and find limited specialization, far below what is feasible given the prevailing production process and average firm size of 5.7 workers. We build and estimate an occupational choice model in which firm size, productivity, and specialization arise endogenously. The model shows that firms in this setting are largely “self-employment in disguise” and generate just a 20% productivity gain over literal self-employment. In a counterfactual economy with full specialization, the same aggregate output can be produced with an average firm size of only 1.6.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supervision at Work - Evidence from a Field Experiment</title>
      <link>https://ritwikasen.github.io/projects/02_supervision/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ritwikasen.github.io/projects/02_supervision/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Abstract&lt;/b&gt;: How does supervision impact worker performance? This paper examines the effects of frontline supervision on the speed and quality of production in a Ugandan data-collection firm. We conducted a field experiment, varying the timing and intensity of supervision among workers, to study the effects of supervision on worker performance. We find that, following increased supervision, workers demonstrate improvements in the dimensions of performance where they were initially weakest. These effects persist, even on days, performance metrics, and tasks that are not directly supervised. Our findings suggest that supervision facilitates targeted on-the-job coaching of workers, which results in economically meaningful improvements in their performance. This underscores the significance of supervisors as conduits for the transmission of tacit production knowledge within organizations.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seeding Innovation through Reality TV</title>
      <link>https://ritwikasen.github.io/projects/03_sirt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ritwikasen.github.io/projects/03_sirt/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bureaucrat–Firm Relationships &amp; the Success of Labor Market Policy</title>
      <link>https://ritwikasen.github.io/projects/04_bureaucrats/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ritwikasen.github.io/projects/04_bureaucrats/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
